# Milos Vasic, curriculum vitae



#### **About**

Milos Vasic is highly-skilled software engineer bringing years in software design, development, and integration (since 2009). Advanced knowledge of Web, Dekstop and Mobile development. Experienced in the full project life cycle from design to implementation to integration.

Languages: Serbian, English, Russian.

#### Contacts and links

• E-Mail: i@mvasic.ru

• Mobile: +381 69 25 35 718 (Serbia), +7 966 323 77 17 (Russian Federation)

• Telegram: milos85vasic

• Networks: Linkedin, TenChat, Xing, VK

• Source code and Open-Source: GitHub, GitFlic, Gitee

## Main programming stacks and technologies

#### Backend development

- GoLang (Gin Gonic)
- Java and Kotlin (Spring / Spring Boot with Maven and Gradle)
- Python (Pyramid, Flask with Waitress)
- Ruby (Ruby on Rails)
- C++ (Drogon with Cmake, Ninja and Konan)

• Docker, Docker Compose

#### Desktop development

- Electron
- Java (Swing and Fx)
- C++ (QT with Qmake or Cmake with Ninja and Konan)
- Flutter (Desktop)
- React Native (Desktop)
- Kotlin Multiplatform (Desktop)
- macOS with Swift

#### Mobile development

- Android, JetPack Compose, MVVP, Retrofit, OkHttp, Firebase, etc.
- Flutter (Dart)
- React Native, Expo, Npm, Yarn
- Kotlin Multiplatform, Kotlin, Kotlin Coroutines
- iOS with Swift (Legacy and Swift UI)

#### Web development

- React
- Angular
- JavaScript and TypeScript
- HTML, CSS

#### **Data and Databases**

- Postrgres
- MySQL
- Sqlite
- Firebase
- MongoDB
- Redis
- Apache Kafka
- RabbitMQ

#### Other and various

- Bash
- Git, SVN, Perforce
- Gradle, MVN, CMake, Ninja, etc.
- JIRA, Confluence, Active Collab
- Jenkins, Travis, Circle Cl, Bitbucket Pipelines, GitHub Actions, All from Harness
- macOS, Linux, Microsoft Windows
- All JetBrains IDEs, GIGA IDE, VSCode, etc.
- XCode
- REST API, WebSockets, SIP, Matrix, SSDP, Quic, etc.

### Work experience

Through the career have been working on the various projects and with various clients.

#### **Fulltime positions**

- Harness Belgrade, Serbia (full-time), from 03/2020 until 12/2024, Staff software engineer (various technologies)
- Leica Geosystems Heerbrugg, Switzerland (full-time), from 02/2016 until 02/2020, Android and iOS developer (with C++ core)
- Bosch Belgrade, Serbia (full-time), from 01/2010 until 01/2016, Android SDK developer

#### Other projects involved

- TN-TECH Novi Sad, Serbia (part-time), from 03/2017
  - o Globex Data (Canada and Switzerland): Sekur (SekurMessenger), SekurMail, SekurSuite
  - BusRide platform
- Increment Loop
  - Yuno
- HelixTrack
- Server Factory
  - Mail Server Factpry
  - o Parallels Utils
  - o Qemu Utils

### Education

- Bachelor of Science: Informatics and Computing, 2008. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)
- M.Sc: Contemporary Information Technologies, 2014. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)